MARK CIUBAL

Roseville, California

(323) 523-3913 | mark.ciubal@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/markciubal/

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Effective at leading or following. Strong desire to collaborate to solve a common problem. Strives for continuous improvement through maximizing efficiency and practicality to accomplish the mission. Background in analysis with a broad knowledge of data visualization techniques. Utilized data mining, and other data analysis techniques to collect, explore, and extract insights from structured and unstructured data. Developed software to apply algorithms to datasets, allowing for large scale experimentation and data driven applications to translate information into intelligence. Experience finding patterns and relationships in data, enabling solutions to a variety of problems and improved strategic decisions.

PROJECTS

CHORECHAMPION - Collaborative project, front and back end work.

https://github.com/markciubal/chore-champion

https://chore-champion-6838d87c31f6.herokuapp.com/

Login: <u>1@1.com</u>, Password: password12345

Tools: JavaScript, Express Handlebars, Bootstrap, Chart.js

Eden - http://eden.markciubal.com/plot.php

A Highcharts.js project that bridged hardware and software, using sensors connected to Arduinos, and Raspberri Pis to update a real-time dashboard.

Tools: PHP, jQuery, mySQL, Python, Arduino and Raspberry Pi

Portfolio - https://markciubal.github.io/portfolio/

GitHub - https://github.com/markciubal

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE: ArcGIS Suite, QGIS, Google Earth, Microsoft Office Suite (Excel, PowerPoint, Word, etc.), Adobe Products (Lightroom, Photoshop, Premiere), Analyst Notebook

WORK EXPERIENCE

School Certifying Official & Technician for Veterans, Web Development & Data Analysis

Sierra College, Rocklin, CA | August 2018 – January 2023

Built tools using React and Chart.js to analyze student data, allowing for predictive modeling for the difficulty of students' course loads. Information was intended to be used to mitigate unnecessary academic difficulties by ensuring students took a manageable curriculum.

Worked with students and supervised 10 Department of Veteran Affairs work-study employees to register, enroll, and enable payment for veterans and their dependents attending Sierra College using their Department of Veterans Affairs education benefits. Tasks include digitizing paperwork, data entry, report generation and customer interaction.

Web Application Developer

Beale Air Force Base, CA | December 2011 – December 2016

Sole developer for HASTE (High-Value Ad-Hoc SIGINT Tracking Environment), a web and Google Earth program using a PHP, MySQL, and jQuery solution to address specific requirements pertaining to a

dynamic target. HASTE required a variety of programming languages and interfaces to build. It improved data comprehension for analysts and leadership. HASTE enabled users to view data in a variety of formats, with an emphasis on enhancing an analyst's awareness of geo-temporal data with machine-assisted pattern analysis.

Training & Documentation Manager

Beale Air Force Base, CA | March 2011 – December 2016

As a SIGINT Fusion Analyst (SFA) program manager, collaborated with resident subject matter experts to identify problems with exploiting a specific SIGINT target set. Trained Air Force analysts during a 3 day ArcGIS course for National Security Agency (NSA) credit. Utilized the expertise of other analysts to develop unique solutions for other problems within the community, including dissemination methods, interactive historic request for information (RFI) solutions, and all-source intelligence analysis.

Senior SIGINT Geospatial Analyst & Digital Network Intelligence Instructor

Camp Pendleton, CA | February 2008 – March 2011

Trained over 75 personnel in Digital Network Intelligence (DNI) and SIGINT Geospatial Metadata Analysis (GMA) as a certified National Cryptologic School (NCS) adjunct instructor. Trained analysts during a 3 day ArcGIS course. While deployed in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom, performed the duties as the senior analyst and liaison officer in a joint service environment. Produced and enforced quality control and dissemination of over 250 time sensitive reports and products. Employed multi-intelligence (SIGINT, HUMINT, IMINT and OSINT) analysis and national level databases to report on and exploit high value targets. Assisted in the disruption of insurgent networks through the use of advanced analytic techniques.

EDUCATION

Formal Education

Projected Completion 2023 - Full-Stack Developer Boot Camp | UC Davis, Online Program A.S. in Natural Sciences | Sierra College, Rocklin, California | May 2020 Projected Completion 2024 - A.S in Computer Science | Sierra College, Rocklin, California Projected Completion 2024 - A.A. in Philosophy | Sierra College, Rocklin, California

Additional Training

Network Exploitation and Target Development Immersion Training (NETA3001)
Training Methods for Cryptologic Instructors (EDUC2501)
Digital Network Intelligence Workshop (NETA2008)
Basic Geospatial Metadata Analysis for Deployers (DEPL2000)
Manual Morse Course (920-SQIA)
Communications Signals Collection and Processing Course (450 Course)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, JavaScript, Handlebars, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, minimal MERN stack experience, Python, GitHub

MILITARY SERVICE

United States Marine Corps | Sergeant | MOS: 2621 | July 2006 – July 2011